# ANDRÉS MAURICIO TRIANA REINA

SYSTEMS ENGINEER

+(57) 3108669185



andrestrianareina@outlook.com (>>



@andresmtr



linkedin.com/in/andres-mauricio-triana-reina/



andrestrianareina.pythonanywhere.com

## **SKILLS AND TOOLS**

**OFFICE** 

EXCEL WORD

POWER POINT

**DATA COLLECTION** 

GOOGLE FORMS
KOBOTOOLBOX

CODING

JUPYTER NOTEBOOK VISUAL STUDIO CODE GOOGLE COLABORATORY

#### **DATA ANALYTICS AND VISUALIZATION**

PYTHON
PANDAS
NUMPY
SEABORN
MATPLOTLIB
PLOTLY
CHART JS
SQL
DATA STUDIO

#### **WEB DEVELOPMENT**

HTML CSS BOOTSTRAP JAVASCRIPT PYTHON DJANGO SQL

## **PROJECT MANAGEMENT**

SLACK TRELLO MICROSOFT TEAMS

## **SOFT SKILLS**

PROBLEM SOLVING CRITICAL THINKING COMMUNICATION TEAMWORK CREATIVITY

## **LANGUAGES**

SPANISH - NATIVE ENGLISH - B1 - B2

## **PROFILE**

Systems engineer with extensive experience in positions such as database management, evaluation and monitoring, construction of management reports and progress indicators, using Python and Excel for extraction, debugging, analysis, visualization of data and information. Strengths in interpreting, analyzing and diagnosing process advances, good at designing and implementing operational plans oriented to timely decision–making.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### (2021 - currently employed)

#### **IMMAP**

#### **Data Analyst Expert**

Compile, debug, process and analytic information from different sources, primary and secondary, using new technologies for processing and analysis of data, artificial intelligence, programming languages and data mining to improve the quality of information about products.

#PYTHON #DJANGO #PANDAS #MATPLOTLIB #WEBSCRAPING #KOBOTOOLBOX #DATA STUDIO #EXCEL #WORD

(2018 - 2021)

#### **IOM - INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATION FOR MIGRATION**

#### **Professional system information**

Manage databases and update report indicators, guaranteeing quality and consistency of information, supporting consolidation of information for internal and external reports.

**#PYTHON #KOBOTOOLBOX #EXCEL #WORD #POWER POINT** 

(2017 - 2018)

## ASOCIACIÓN COLOMBIANA DE DISTRIBUIDORES PELÍCULAS CINEMATOGRÁFICAS

#### Manage databases - Cadbox

Manage databases of movie tickets sold in Colombia and update the information in the CADBOX app. In addition, manage users in the system and create reports for associates.

(2013 - 2017) FUPAD/FUCOLDE

#### Analyst as evaluation and monitoring

Manage, creation and depuration of databases with the purpose to build information, reports and indicators.

#EXCEL #WORD #POWER POINT #GOOGLE FORMS

## **EDUCATION**

(2017 - 2020)

UNAD - UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL ABIERTA Y A DISTANCIA.

Systems engineer

(2014 - 2016)

SENA - SERVICIO NACIONAL DE APRENDIZAJE

Technology in analysis and development of information systems

# **COURSES/CERTIFICATIONS**

Comprehensive SQL Bootcamp : Beginner to Advanced - Udemy SQL course - Sololearn

Interactive Python Dashboards with Plotly and Dash - Udemy Python for Data Sciences and machine learning Bootcamp - Udemy

Big Data Analytics: Opportunities, Challenges and the future - Future Learn Google Curso de introducción al desarrollo web: HTML y CSS - Google activate

Python course - Sololearn